Guide to the Victor F. Germack and Lori Shepard Germack Collection of Photographs of Indians of North America
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Card Photographs, 1863-circa 1910; Series II; 1.67; (3 boxes)
  - Cabinet Photographs
    - Gardner, Alexander
      - Afraid of the Bear (Mato Kokipa, Ma-To-Ko-Kepa, or Niato-ko-kepa ), Yanktonai Indian Man, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 117)
      - Bloody Mouth (Wi-Cha-I-We or E-Wa-Hu or E-Wa-He-A), Hunkpapa Indian Man, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 118)
      - Eagle Man, Human Male War Eagle, or Man Who Packs the Eagle (Wicha Wanbdi, Wica Wanbli, or Whoe-A-Ke), Yanktonai Indian Man, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 119)
      - Wife of Eagle Man, Human Male War Eagle, or Man Who Packs the Eagle (Wicha Wanbdi, Wica Wanbli, Whoe-A-Ke), Yanktonai Indian Man, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 120)
      - Long Fox or Long Buffalo Bull (Ta-Tan-Ka-Han-Ska), Dakota Indian Man, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 121)
      - Medicine Bear, Medicine Bear Track, or Mysterious Grizzly Bear (Mato Wakan, Ma-To-Ican, Ma-To-O-A-Wa-Kan, or Ma-To-Wuh-Kan), Yanktonai Indian Man, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 122)
      - Two Grizzly Bears or Two Bears (Matononpa or Ma-To-No-Pah), Yanktonai Indian Man, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 123)
      - Used as a Shield or John Grass (Waha-Canka-Yapi, Pehzi, or Pah-Zhe), Sihasapa Indian Man, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 124)
      - Walking Crane (Pe-han-sa-a-ma-ni, Pehansanmani, Pa-ha-sa-mana, or Pa-sa-ga-o-ma-na), Dakota Indian Man, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 125)
      - Walking Shooter (Wa-Ku-Ta-A-Ma-Ni, Wah-Koo-Ta-Mon-Ih, or Wakute Mani), Hunkpapa Indian Man, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Goff, Orlando Scott
      - Chief Joseph or Young Joseph (Hin-mah-too-yah-lat-kekt or Hinmatóowyalahtq'it), Nez Percé Indian Man, 1877 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Hartwell, Francis Asher
      Photographs probably created by his assistant, Charles Dossick.
      - Maricopa Indian Chief with Birds Over His Shoulders (No. 8), 1898 January (Box 3, Folder 128)
      - Chief Charley Juan Saul, Maricopa Indian Man (No. 17), 1898 January (Box 3, Folder 129)
      - Wife of Chief Charley Juan Saul, Maricopa Indian, 1898 January (Box 3, Folder 130)
      - Pima Beauty (No. 451), 1898 January (Box 3, Folder 131)
      - Navajo Indian Man (No. 474), 1898 January (Box 3, Folder 132)
      - Apache Indian Girl (No. 508), 1898 January (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Haynes, Frank Jay
      - Little Head, Crow Indian Man, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 134)
      - American Indian Infant in a Papoose and Cradleboard, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 135)
      - Running Deer or Hoop-on the Forehead, Crow Indian Man, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 136)
      - Yellow Dog or Old Coyote, Crow Indian Man (No.2870), 1883 (Box 3, Folder 137-138)
      - Yellow Dog or Old Coyote and Squaws, Crow Indians, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Hilton, E. F.
      - Osage Indian Medicine Man and a European American Man, circa 1890 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Hodson, John R.
      - Domingo Dick, an Albino Chukchansi Indian Infant Boy, 1892 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Houseworth, Thomas
      - Donald McKay, Chief of the Warm Springs Indians, circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Kirk, Joseph
      - Tswawadi, Kwakiutl Indian Man, circa 1904 (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - LaRoche, Frank
      - Copy Photograph of Seattle (Si'ahl), Chief of the Duwamish and Suquamish Indians (No.1 1/2), circa 1890 (Box 3, Folder 144)
        Original photograph by Edward M. Sammis.
    - Livingston, George
      - Kiowa Indian Boy, circa 1910 (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - Markey, Daniel A.
      - Towlkli (Tol-Cly), A San Carlos Indian Chief Who Presented President and Mrs. Cleveland a Buckskin Baby, circa 1885-1890 (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - Parsons, George W.
      - Group of Osage Indian Dancers in Front of a Wooden Building with a Roof of Tree Branches in Gray Horse, Indian Territory, circa 1890-1900 (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - Randall, A. Frank
      - Augustine, Head Chief of White Clan Jicarilla Apache, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - Savage, Charles Roscoe
      - Ute Indian Boy, circa 1895 (Box 3, Folder 149)
      - Ute Indians, Two Women and Three Children, circa 1895 (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - Scott, George W.
      - Mad Bear (Mahto Ocinsica or Mato Knaskiyan), Dakota Indian Man, circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 151)
      - Yellow Horn and Wolf, American Indian Men (possibly Crow, Hidatsa, or Crow Indians), the Latter Holding a Cabinet Photograph, circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - Scribner & Cosand
      - Cheyenne Indian Girl on a Horse, circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 153)
      - Two Cheyenne Indian Girls, circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 154)
      - First Sergeant Weat of the Indian Scouts, Wife, and Daughter, Cheyenne Indians, circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - Soule, William Stinson
      - Gray Goose or Cry of the Wild Goose (Saloso, Tsau-lau-te, or Tsa'l-aute), son of White Bear (Sa-tant-ta), Kiowa Indian, 1867 (Box 3, Folder 156)
      - Satanta or Sa-tant-ta (White Bear), Kiowa Indian War Chief, 1867 (Box 3, Folder 157)
      - Lone Wolf the Elder (Gui-pah-gho or Guipago), Kiowa Indian Man, 1870 (Box 3, Folder 158)
    - Spencer, George E.
      - Kate Huston of the Buffalo Bill Wild West Show, Dakota Indian Woman, circa 1890 (Box 3, Folder 159)
    - Stiff, Charles W.
      - General George R. Crook with Four Teton Indians, circa 1873-1875 (Box 3, Folder 160)
        Manuscript dedication on the verso, To Milo from, followed by phonetic spelling of the names of the individuals pictured, probably in Lakota.
    - Toogood, Franklin William
      - Julia Quakano Pokagon, Potawatomi Indian, circa 1890 (Box 3, Folder 161)
    - Trager, George E.
      - Red Cloud (Mahpíya Lúta), Oglala Indian, 1890-1891 (Box 3, Folder 162)
      - Father Francis M. Craft, 1891 December 29 (Box 3, Folder 163)
    - United States Geological and Geographical Survey of the Territories
      Letterpress captions on mounts: "Department of the Interior, U.S. Geological Survey, F. V. Hayden, U.S. Geologist in Charge."
      Captions in the negative.
      - British (Nac-a-rash), Iowa Indian Man, 1869 (Box 3, Folder 164)
        Photograph by Charles Milton Bell.
      - Little Robe (Hah-Ket-Home-Mah or Ski'o-Mah), Cheyenne Indian Man, 1871 (Box 3, Folder 165)
        Photograph by Jeremiah Gurney and Benjamin Gurney.
      - Afraid of the Eagle, The Eagle Fears Him, or One Afraid of the Eagle (Wan-Bli-Ko-Ki-Pa) (No. 309), Oglala Indian Man, 1872 May (Box 3, Folder 166)
        Photograph by Alexander Gardner.
      - Long Soldier, Waco Indian Man, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 167)
      - Wife of Cheevers (He Goat), a Comanche Indian Woman, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 168)
      - Bear Wolf or Packs the Bear (Se-ta-pit-se) and his Wife, Stays with the Horses, Crow Indians, 1873 (Box 3, Folder 169)
        Photograph by Julius Ulke and Henry Ulke.
      - Rushing Bear (Ku-Nugh-Na-Give-Nuk), Arikara Indian Man, 1874; (2 photographic prints) (Box 3, Folder 170)
      - Eagle Plume or Eagle Headdress (Quyulange), Kansa Indian Man, 1877 (Box 3, Folder 171)
      - Oscar Mark or Little Vessel, Wasco Indian Man, 1877 (Box 3, Folder 172)
    - Walker Indian View Co.
      - Bemidji (Shay-now-ish-kung), Ojibwa Indian Man., circa 1900 (Box 3, Folder 173)
      - Flat Mouth (Ne-gon-e-bin-ais), Ojibwa Indian Man, circa 1900 (Box 3, Folder 174)
    - Unidentified Photographers
      - American Indian Camp with Wooden Buldings and Canvas Tents, 1877 (Box 3, Folder 175)
      - Copy Photograph of Spotted Tail (Sinte-Galeska, Cin-Te-Gi-Le-Ska, or Tshin-Ta-Ge-Las-Kah), Brulé Indian Man, 1872, circa 1886-1900 (Box 3, Folder 176)
      - Studio portrait of Two American Indian Men and Two American Indian Women in Indian Territory, circa 1895 (Box 3, Folder 177)
  - Imperial Photographs
    Introduced circa 1863, imperial photographs were photographic prints mounted on cardboard with dimensions approximately 17.5 by 25.4 centimeters (6.9 by 10 inches), as well as 20 by 25.1 centimeters (7.9 by 9.9 inches).
    This format is distinct from another format also known as imperial photographs, introduced in 1856, with print dimensions approximately 43.2 centimeters by 53.3 centimeters (17 by 20 inches).
    - Barry, David Francis
      - Fort Yates and Indian Agency, Dakota Territory (No.926), circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 178)
    - Grabill, John C. H.
      - Group portrait of Miniconjou Indian from the Band of Big Foot's at a Grass Dance on or near the Cheyenne River Indian Reservation and the Cheyenne River, South Dakota (No. 3654), 1890 August 9 (Box 3, Folder 179)
      - Indian Girls Home; a Group of Miniconjou Indians Girls with Visiting Officers and Indian Police at Big Foot's Village on the Pine Ridge Indian Reservation, South Dakota (No. 2658), 1890 (Box 3, Folder 180)
    - Locke, Henry R.
      - Indian Parade July 4th, 1895, Crow Agency, Montana, on the Burlington & Missouri River Railroad (No. 28), 1895 July 4 (Box 3, Folder 181)
    - Shindler, A. Zeno
      - Copy photograph of a Daguerreotype Portrait of Keokuk (Watchful Fox), Sauk Indian, Originally Created in 1847, 1868 (Box 3, Folder 182)
    - Unidentified Photographers
      - Photographs of Fort Elliott, Texas
        The same unidentified photographer created this group of imperial photographs that depict Fort Ellis, Texas, as well as a boudoir photograph.
        - Cheyenne and Arapahoe Indian Scouts, Troop C, Under the command of Lieutenant Homer W. Wheeler at Fort Elliott, Texas, 1890; 2 photographic prints on the same mount (Box 3, Folder 183)
        - Cheyenne Indian Camp with Roasted Dogs, Fort Elliott, Texas, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 184)
        - Quarters of Captain William Anman and Family at Fort Elliott, Texas, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 185)
        - Quarters of Captain Walter Scribner Schuyler at Fort Elliott, Texas, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 186)
        - Chaplain Captain Robert McWatty and his Wife, as well as their Quarters, at Fort Elliott, Texas, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 187)
        - Haunted House, Fort Elliott, Texas, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 188)
        - Hospital at Fort Elliott, Texas, 1890; (1 boudoir photograph) (Box 3, Folder 189)
      - Family of Horse Thieves Sitting on Steps of Building at Fort Custer, Montana, circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 190)
      - Exterior Portrait of American Indian, Nine Men and Eight Women, Possibly Sihasapa Indians or Crow Indians, and Two European American Men, circa 1890 (Box 3, Folder 191)
  - Promenade Photographs
    Arranged alphabetically by photographer or studio followed by a photograph made by an unidentified creator.
    Introduced in 1875, the promenade photograph format measures approximately 9.5 by 19 centimeters (3.75 x 7 inches).
    - Brown, W. Henry
      Photographs from a set, "A Trip from Trinidad, Colorado, through New Mexico to Paso-del-Norte, Mexico."
      - Glorieta Pass, New Mexico (No.372), circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 192)
      - Socorro, New Mexico (No.373), circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 193)
      - Las Vegas, New Mexico (No.369), circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 194)
    - Unidentified Photographer
      - Mule Team Hauling Ore from Caillie, New Mexico, 1887 (Box 3, Folder 195)
  - Boudoir Photographs
    Introduced in the 1870s, the boudoir photograph format measures approximately 12.7 x 20.9 centimeters (5 by 8.25 inches).
    - Chase, Dana B.
      - Navajo Chief and Son (No. 195), circa 1886 (Box 3, Folder 196)
      - Ute Indian girl from Pojoaque, New Mexico (No 83), circa 1886 (Box 3, Folder 197)
      - Plaza, Principal Square in Santa Fe, New Mexico, in Winter (No. 2), circa 1890 (Box 3, Folder 198)
      - Cathedral of Saint Francis of Assisi and Hospital of the Sisters of Charity, Santa Fe, New Mexico (No. 19), circa 1890 (Box 3, Folder 199)
      - Ancient Pueblo of Tesuque, New Mexico, East Side (No. 29), circa 1890 (Box 3, Folder 200)
      - Apache Indians, Mother and Children, after the Children Have Had Two Years' Schooling (No. 85), circa 1890 (Box 3, Folder 201)
      - Santa Fe from Old Fort Marcy, New Mexico (No. 128), circa 1890 (Box 3, Folder 202)
      - Indian Ghost Dance, circa 1890 (Box 3, Folder 203)
    - Cross, William Richard
      - Copy Photograph of Sixteen Portraits and Depictions of American Indians, 1878-1898 (Box 3, Folder 204-206)
    - Fuller, Myron A.
      - Sioux Indians -- Braves & Beauties. Rapid City, 1884 July 4 (Box 3, Folder 207)
    - Guernsey, Byron H.
      - Los Pueblo de Taos, New Mexico (No. 2075), 1878; (2 photographic prints) (Box 3, Folder 208)
    - Harlan, Andrew James
      - North Slope Gold Hill, Cripple Creek, Colorado, circa 1897 (Box 3, Folder 209)
    - Hook, William Edward
      - Carriage Road to Manitou Grand Caverns, Colorado (No. 437), circa 1890 (Box 3, Folder 210)
      - Seven Falls in South Cheyenne Canyon, Colorado (No. 103), circa 1890 (Box 3, Folder 211)
    - Kaadt, Christian G.
      - Indian Dance, San Juan, New Mexico, circa 1890 (Box 3, Folder 212)
    - Martin, Alexander
      - Devil's Gate High Bridge on the Georgetown Loop near Georgetown, Colorado., circa 1883-1890 (Box 3, Folder 213)
    - Mitchell & DeGroff
      Partnership of E. S. Mitchell and C. E. De Groff.
      - Opening of the Oklahoma Territory (No.71), 1889 April 27 (Box 3, Folder 214)
    - Moon, Thomas C.
      - American Indian Man, as well as European American Men, Women, and a Boy, Among Tents, Probably in Laconia, New Hampshire, circa 1890 (Box 3, Folder 215)
    - Standiford, Jacob F.
      - Boomers Going West; European American settlers and covered wagons en route to unassigned lands ceded to the United States by the Creek (Muskogee) and Seminole Indians, circa 1879 (Box 3, Folder 216)
      - Ferry on the Arkansas River with a stagecoach that travelled between Muskogee and Fort Gibson, circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 217)
    - Trager, George E.
      - Stinking Bear, a Lakota Indian; Hollow Wood, a Northern Cheyenne Indian; and Crazy Bear, a Lakota Indian, all on Horseback at the Pine Ridge Agency, South Dakota, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 218)
      - War Dance Ceremony of the Lakota Indians showing a Wounded Indian in front of the Post Office at the Pine Ridge Agency, South Dakota, circa 1891 (Box 3, Folder 219)
    - Wittick, Benjamin
      - Zuni Woman and Water Olla, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 220)
      - Anselina, Navajo Indian Woman, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 221)
      - Cha-si-to, White Mountain Apache Indian and Son of Bonito, with a Mescal Fiddle, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 222)
      - Navajo Indian Silversmith, in Native Dress with Tools, Blankets, and Ornaments Inside Brush Arbor, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 223)
      - Vicente and his Wife, Anselina, Navajo Indians, 1883; (2 photographic prints) (Box 3, Folder 224)
      - Apache Indian Babies, Two Infants, circa 1883 (Box 3, Folder 225)
      - Bonito, Chiricahua Indian Man, circa 1883 (Box 3, Folder 226)
      - Bonito, White Mountain Apache Indian Man, circa 1883 (Box 3, Folder 227)
      - Old Loco or One Eye Lost, Chief of Warm Spring Apache Indians, circa 1883 (Box 3, Folder 228)
      - Peaches (Tzoeh or Penaltish), an Apache Indian Man, Posed Standing Between Two Seated Unidentified Apache Indian Men, circa 1883 (Box 3, Folder 229)
      - Ze-le and his Wife, Tzes-ton, Chiricahua Apache Indians, circa 1883 (Box 3, Folder 230)
      - Na-Buash-i-Ta, Na-Buash-Ta, or Na-Bau-Shhi-Ta, White Mountain Apache Indian Medicine Man, circa 1884 (Box 3, Folder 231)
      - Possibly Casimiro Grigolha, an American Indian Interpreter who Served with Colonel George Pearson Buell and Colonel Eugene Asa Carr in the Victorio Campaign, circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 232)
      - Chuna and Baby, Navajo Indian Woman Carrying her Infant in a O-ue-tzal (Cradleboard), circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 233)
      - Dutch, an Apache Indian Scout who served with Captain Emmet Crawford, circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 234)
      - Kai-i-tumi. Albino Zuni Indian man, circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 235)
      - Luli-pah and Sowatcha, Mohave Indian Women, circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 236)
      - Mangas, Chief of Warm Springs Apache Indians, Son of Mangas Coloradas (Dasoda-hae ), circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 237)
      - Mariano, Chief of Navajo Indians, circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 238)
      - Hopi Indian Woman from Sichomovi or Oraibi, Arizona, circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 239)
      - Nana, Broken Foot, or Angry, He is Agitated (Kas-tziden or Haškenadiltla), Chief of Warm Spring Apache Indians, circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 240)
      - Navajo Indian Woman, Girl, and Nursing Infant in Cradleboard, circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 241)
      - Patricio Pino (Balawahdiwa, Pahlowatiwa, Paliwhatiwa, or Pali-wah-ti-wa), Governor of Zuni, circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 242)
      - Sergeant Jim, White Mountain Apache Indian Scout who served with Captain Emmet Crawford, circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 243)
      - Sta-Yeshi or Esta-Yeshi (Old Nell or Nelly), Navajo Woman and Sister of Mariano, the Chief of Navajo Indians, circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 244)
      - Tzashima, Laguna Indian Woman, circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 245)
      - Zuni Pueblo (Shiwinna), circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 246)
      - Navajo Indian Scouts, Biziz, Gayetenito and Pedro, Apache Campaign of 1886 (Box 3, Folder 247)
      - Largo, Navajo Indian Man and Scout who Served with Captain Benjamin H. Rogers, 1886 (Box 3, Folder 248)
      - Vicenti, Pitacio and Juana, Navajo Indians, circa 1886 (Box 3, Folder 249)
      - Gayetenito and Malia, Navajo Indian Man and Woman, circa 1887 (Box 3, Folder 250)
    - Unidentified Photographers
      - Oxen Team with Three Pueblo Indians and a European American Man. Albuquerque, New Mexico, circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 251)
      - Exterior Portrait of American Indians Consisting of Fifteen Women and Twenty Children, circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 252)
  - Victoria Cards
    Introduced circa 1870-1871, the Victoria card format measures approximately 12.7 x 8.3 (5 by 3.25 inches).
    - Heller, Louis Herman
      - Jefferson C. Davis Riddle, The Boy with Pretty Eyes, or The Handsome Boy (Char-Ka or Charka), Boy with Modoc Indian and European American Ancestry, 1873 (Box 3, Folder 253)
      - Toby Riddle, Tobey Riddle, or The Woman of the Brave Heart (Nannookdoowah, Wi-Ne-Ma, or Winema), a Modoc Indian Woman, 1873 (Box 3, Folder 254)
    - Petit, Pierre
      Portraits of American Indian men in Jardin Zoologique d'Acclimatation (also known as l'Acclimatation Anthropologique) in the northern portion of the Bois de Boulogne in Paris, France.
      - American Indian Man and his Horse, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 255)
      - American Indian Man in Bearskin Robe, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 256)
  - Other Card Photographs
    This group of material includes card photographs with dimensions that do not fit within the defined attributes of traditional classes.
    - American Tobacco Company
      Copy photographs distributed on cigarette cards for Old Fashion cigarettes.
      - Copy photograph of a portrait of Chief Joseph or Young Joseph (Hin-mah-too-yah-lat-kekt or Hinmatóowyalahtq'it), Nez Percé Indian, by David Francis Barry in 1877, circa 1890 (Box 3, Folder 257)
      - Copy photograph Curly or Curley (Ash-Ish-Ish-E), a Crow Indian and United States Army Scout, by Frank Jay Haynes in 1890, circa 1890 (Box 3, Folder 258)
    - Baker & Johnston
      Studio operated by Charles S. Baker and Eli Johnston in Evanston, Wyoming.
      - Shoshone War Dance, 1884 (Box 3, Folder 259)
    - Barry, David Francis
      - Gall (Phizí), Teton Indian Man, Wearing Large Crucifix and Leather Jacket., circa 1883-1889 (Box 20, Folder 260)
      - Rain in the Face (Ité Omágažu, Iromagaja, or Itonagaju), a Dakota Indian Man, circa 1885 (Box 20, Folder 261)
    - Bell, Charles Milton
      - Spotted Tail or Jumping Buffalo (Siŋté Glešká, Sinte-Galeshka, or Tshin-Tah-Ge-Las-Kah), Brulé Indian Man, circa 1873 (Box 24, Folder 262)
      - On-A-Wat (Cannot Do It or Can't Do it), Fox Indian Man, circa 1890 (Box 24, Folder 262a)
        Attributed to Charles Milton Bell.
    - Bonine, Elias A.
      - Yuma Indian Squaw (No. 10), circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 263)
      - Yuma Indian Man (No. 41), circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 264)
      - Two Yuma Warriors (No. 52), circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 265)
      - Three Yuma Indian Women (No. 85), circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 266)
      - Yuma Indian Squaw (No. 97), circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 267)
    - Cummings, Everett George
      - Interior of the Lewiston National Bank, Lewiston, Idaho, circa 1892 (Box 20, Folder 268)
        Pencil inscription on the recto by J. Howard Howe that identifies him in the image.
    - Davis, Robert M.
      - Copy Photograph of Crystal Creek in the Black Canyon of the Gunnison, Colorado, circa 1880-1886 (Box 3, Folder 269)
        Original photograph by William Henry Jackson.
      - Marshall Pass, Colorado, West From Summit, circa 1880-1886 (Box 3, Folder 270)
    - Fair, Henry
      - Interior of Lewiston National Bank Cashing United States Government Checks for Nez Percé Indians at Lapwai, Nez Percé Indian Reservation, Idaho, 1895 August 15 (Box 20, Folder 271)
        Identified from left to right: Fred Bremmer of the Kendrick Bank; Three Feathers (Mah-tot-wap-tus); Samuel Martin, clerk at the Nez Percé Indian Reservation; Red Horn (Teh-was-in-pilpt); Eddie Conner, mixed race Nez Percé Indian interpreter; and J. Howard Howe representing the Lewiston National Bank, Lewiston, Idaho.
        Affixed typescript description on the recto describes the context for the photograph, as well as an ink inscription by Howe.
    - Grabill, John C. H.
      - General Nelson Appleton Miles and Staff Viewing the Largest Hostile Indian Camp in the United States, near Pine Ridge, South Dakota (No. 3527), 1891 January 16 (Box 20, Folder 272)
      - Exterior Group Portrait of Dakota Indian Men and Children, Part of the cast of Buffalo Bill's Wild West Show, as well as European American Interpreter George C. Crager, 1892 (Box 20, Folder 273)
    - Haynes, Frank Jay
      - Crater of the Splendid Geyser (No. 4568), circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 274)
      - Sawmill Geyser (No. 4575), circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 275)
      - Sponge Geyser in Action (No. 4578), circa 1885 (Box 3, Folder 276)
    - Irwin, William E.
      - Cruis, His Two Wives, and a Girl, Comanche Indians, circa 1900 (Box 3, Folder 277)
      - Millie Oytant, Kiowa Indian Woman, circa 1900 (Box 3, Folder 278)
    - Jackson, William Henry
      This group of photographic prints by Jackson was originally collected in Colorado by Benjamin W. H. Peckham (1864-1923) in 1887.
      - Black Lake, Blue River Mountains, Colorado (No. 2221), circa 1881-1887 (Box 3, Folder 279)
      - Devil's Slide, Weber Canon, Utah (No. 4603), circa 1882-1887 (Box 3, Folder 280)
      - Manitou, Colorado (No. 424), 1886 (Box 3, Folder 281)
      - Old Faithful Geyser, Yellowstone National Park, circa 1870-1887 (Box 3, Folder 282)
      - United States Signal Station on Pike's Peak, Colorado (No. 421), 1879-1887 (Box 3, Folder 283)
      - Rainbow Falls in Winter, on Twin Creek, Ute Pass near Woodland Park, Colorado. (No. 408), circa 1880-1887 (Box 3, Folder 284)
      - Royal Gorge, Denver & Rio Grande Railway and Hanging Bridge over the Arkansas River, Colorado (No. 804), circa 1881-1887 (Box 3, Folder 285)
      - Shoshone Falls on the Snake River, Idaho (No. 5401A), circa 1882 and 1887 (Box 3, Folder 286)
    - Long, George
      - Geronimo (Goyaałé), Chiricahua Indian Man, circa 1895 (Box 3, Folder 287)
    - Martin, Alexander
      - Hanging Rock in Clear Creek Canyon, Colorado, Looking Up (No. 2000), circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 288)
      - Georgetown, Colorado (No. 2201), circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 289)
      - Idaho Springs, Colorado, From the East (No. 2280), circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 290)
      - Inspiration Point in Clear Creek Canyon, Colorado (No. 2003), circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 291)
      - Mother Grundy in Clear Creek Canyon, Colorado (No. 2002), circa 1880 (Box 3, Folder 292)
      - Silver Plume and Mines, Colorado (No. 2011), circa 1880-1884 (Box 3, Folder 293)